Is that the Tokyo Met building?
That's just a regular office building.
Why? Where are you trying to go?
I'm heading to Tokyo City Esperion Soccer Town.
They're holding tryouts today.
I'm hoping to snag a spot on the youth team.
Ohhhh!
All this is a soccer facility?
It looks like a battleship!
They must all be here for tryouts, too.
Well, guess I better get out there and start practicing.
Oh, right. The registration fee.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Are you... from Ehime?
Uh, yeah, but what gave it away?
All this hair.
I was told some guy with hair like Valderamas was gonna show up.
My brother's the one who said it, not me.
But I'd say he's right.
Oh, really?
Cut that out!
Stay out of my personal space! I don't even know you!
Whatever.
My bro won't shut up about you, so I don't see you as a stranger.
It's so annoying.
Eh?
Come on, Hana! Hurry it up!
We're about to get started with tryouts.
Hey! Coming!
Uh...
Here for tryouts? Right this way! Follow me!
We have a total of 86 hopefuls. I have noticed some promising candidates.
Soichiro Tachibana from Yokoyama Musashino's junior youth soccer team.
He's determined and strong.
He was on the team that won the Kanto Boys soccer tournament.
Next we have...
Akinori Kaneda.
He's the captain of the prestigious Tama Central junior high team.
There's Yudai Hasegawa from Seiran junior high.
And Lee Yong-suk, who's from Seiran as well.
What about you? Done anything of real note, Nahime?
Ugh.
I have no idea what my brother was thinking.
Did you pay your fee yet?
The front desk's over there. 5,000 yen.
Good luck. Knock him dead.
See ya.
Oh, wow!
A grass field!
I can't believe I get to play soccer on such a beautiful field on such a beautiful day!
Man, I wish Shun could see this. He'd love it too!
I'm Date, the head coach.
Some of you may already be aware, but this will be our ninth year in J1.
And we've accomplished quite a bit.
Some background on our team.
We've won the league title, and also the Emperor's Cup.
First team's record's solid gold.
It's all because of how well our youth players are trained.
Experience coaching is considered the finest in all Japan, especially for youth.
I'll let you take it from here, Manager Fukuda.
Good to see you guys. Thanks for coming out here today.
A team that fails to nurture the next generation has no future.
Realistically, though, pro soccer clubs end up having to acquire players from other organizations all the time to help balance out any weaknesses on their team.
And then, sometimes, the player ends up being a letdown.
Tragic.
Well, that doesn't happen with players that we've been training ever since they were young.
We know their skills and personalities better than anyone.
We understand their strengths and weaknesses.
These benefits can all be yours as well.
Training with us will allow you to absorb the club's style of play.
That's what it means when we say we raise players.
We believe the future of Japanese soccer lies there.
If you pass today, then we'll work together.
And if you don't, use it.
Use this experience to help grow and become a better player.
Then come back and laugh at us for not seeing your potential.
Let's go!
That sounded good. What'd you think, Benzin?
If it was good, then you just ruined it.
Aw, crap!
I barely know anything about the J League or youth teams.
Or this club, for that matter.
I only came to this thing because he asked me to.
And still, I can't stop freaking out about it.
Ugh, this kinda sucks!
One more thing before we start.
It's rare for us to select new players from these tryouts,
so don't get your hopes up.
Start getting used to the fact that we might not pick any of you.
Huh?
Why'd you wait till now to tell us that, old man?
Watch your tone, kid! Show some dare respect!
But it's not fair!
Look how many people came here to try to get in!
And you're saying you might decide not to pick anyone?
That's just wrong!
Ooh, smart mouth's in for it now.
Oh, you're right. I guess I forgot to mention that.
Hm?
Sorry it slipped my mind, Ashito.
Everything piled up and we were running out of time.
My bad!
What? Why is he wearing sandals?
This team is managed by a crazy, creepy old man!
What?
This team is not going to play ground soccer.
We only take players who are game-ready.
Look.
Last year, with all the players one year above you,
we added 15 players to the team.
Of these only three of them were scouted.
We only found one at tryouts.
And the rest were promoted from the junior youth team.
Promoted? I didn't know that.
Yeah. I'd say most of the time over half of our youth team is made up of players who were doing very well on the junior youth team.
Last year, we had 25 third-year students working out on our junior youth team alone.
That means 14 hard-working kids believed they'd be promoted, and they were not.
Then we have the scouted players.
Talon scouts are always buzzing around Tokyo's soccer fields looking for the next star player.
If we discover someone worthwhile, we'll negotiate directly with that kid to join the team right then and there.
Oh, so you're saying I wasn't worthwhile to you, you lame old geezer?
Basically, our scouts have done all the work needed to find the best players, and you were not among them.
86 of you here were initially passed on. 86 of you who weren't worth an immediate negotiation.
That's really harsh, man. Why are you saying it like that?
Fook it out.
But here's the thing. This doesn't come as a surprise to any of you, does it?
You know you're not there yet, but you still came to take a chance on a slim possibility.
So many of you want to join Tokyo City Asperion. Bad enough, you still showed up.
Players with passion strong enough to change their game really do shine through in a crowd like this.
That kind of spark is essential to this club. It's a spirit of defiance.
A player who will be determined to turn tables. Man, I'd kill to have players like that.
Light that spark today, and we will find our way to you.
Show us what you got.
First things first, we need each one of you to take this fitness test.
6.01.
Bro, why are you shaking?
Whoa, looks like I am, too.
Oh, my stomach hurts when I'm nervous.
Owie.
You're the first other candidate to speak to me since I got here. Congrats!
I'm Ashito Aoi. My position is Genius Forward.
I'm Esaku Otomo.
But I don't care about your name. You're ruining everything for me.
Huh?
You couldn't keep your stupid mouth shut.
So manager Fukuda decided to give us that fluffy speech.
And now these losers are fired up.
At first, they were shaking like the autumn leaves out there.
I actually had a chance to psych those guys out.
Oh, is that so?
Hmm?
You're right. We were all nervous when we got here.
But I think it'll be even more fun this way.
Huh?
I get to play soccer with all of these guys at their best.
Next, we'll do 20-minute games.
Teams of seven-on-seven.
The most important part of the first stage.
Good luck out there, everybody.
What the hell kind of moron put these teams together?
This is so unfair.
Bring it on.
Hey there, big brother!
How's the grading going?
Hana, I told you not to call me that when we're on the field.
Oh, right.
Sorry about that, sir.
Hey, listen, Hana.
I didn't realize it was going to be so hot out here.
You're the manager's sister, so feel free to take a break.
It's cool.
I'm sure it's a whole lot worse for all the guys out there.
Their careers are on the line.
Although, not all of them seem to be talented.
It feels very one-sided.
Hey, what are you doing?
Quit the ball hogging.
You're not the only one playing this game, Ehime.
Stop giving the ball away.
What am I supposed to do when none of you will pass me the ball?
All I want to do is score.
And since you won't pass it to me, I have to take it upfield myself.
No one's passing it to you because you never passed back.
You come out here yapping about how genius of a player you are,
but you're just another annoying, obnoxious show-off.
You make big moves, and I can respect that.
It's not entirely your fault.
We're pure chaos.
Our teamwork sucks.
We need to pull it together.
Looks like they've got some trouble on the white team.
That doesn't surprise me one bit.
They're getting eaten alive out there.
That's how Ichiro Tachibana kid is outshining them all.
What the heck was that?
Rumor has it that these tryouts are just for show,
and the real reason behind them is to work out whether or not to sign him up right away.
Nice!
I'm free over here!
Hey, I'm free!
What the?
Don't worry, Kaneda.
It was a nice try!
Yo, bro.
Is it normal to have such a huge skill gap between the teams?
Hmm?
Hmph.
These tryouts aren't about entire teams.
Individual careers are at stake here.
They're all fighting to stand out and be better than the guy next to them.
It's all me, me, me.
Being thrown into a makeshift team where no one knows each other
makes it near impossible to show off one's A-game.
They're serving their own needs in the moment,
wondering which role to play in this unusual and imperfect situation.
The thing is, we aren't judging their physicality or techniques.
We're judging their ability to think, their intelligence.
That kid from A-Hime?
He's done.
He's just completely frozen on the field.
I don't know what manager Fukuda was thinking having him come out.
He's worthless.
Damn it.
Why can't I stop doing this?
But you're just another annoying, obnoxious show-off!
I'm used to being on a team with friends, people who know me,
and they'd let me play the way that I wanted.
As long as I live, I will never forget that.
But playing with these guys is something else.
They've all got their own skills.
It'll be harder to beat them.
Real soccer players.
Ruthless strategies.
This is what soccer should feel like!
Yes.
Otomo!
Does he know how to play this game?
He's a forward, but he dropped all the way into defense for some reason.
I seriously hope he's not trying to make a grandstand play this late in the game.
Is your brain working, A-Hime?
Come on!
Pass it back to me!
What's wrong with you?
The ball's way too close to our goal.
Move!
Don't leave with regrets!
You all only got five minutes to go!
Almost there!
I can do this!
Sucks he came all the way from A-Hime.
Eh, there's no way he's making the cut after that.
Dammit!
What the heck is that freak doing?
Come on!
I'm begging you!
Take one more step in this direction!
This is insane.
Why is A-Hime holding the ball in that area?
He better have some wicked move coming up.
Check out Captain Crazy Hair.
Is that a panic attack or what?
Yeah.
If we apply pressure, we can take it.
Let's go!
What's wrong with him?
Why is he dribbling towards his own goal?
Kaneda, get going!
Ethan!
Awesome!
Way to be there, Kaneda!
That was me!
I'm the one who told him to start running!
If I hadn't, you wouldn't have moved, right?
Huh?
Hey!
Did you guys see that?
I'm the guy who shines even when he doesn't score!
Name's Ashito Aoi!
Remember it!
Aoi, Aoi, Aoi, Aoi!
Well, I didn't really expect that to work.
It was pure luck.
Hm.
I gotta admit, assists feel great.
Oh?
Hm.
That was so amazing!
I can't even believe it was real!
Such brilliant timing, wasn't it?
As the forward, he dropped all the way into his own end of the field to bait the opposition.
Even their defenders left the goal!
That created an opening on the other end for a fraction of a second,
and then he sent a long pass upfield!
And it glided with pinpoint precision!
That play told me who he was.
It's just like I got a bird's eye view of his perspective of the entire soccer field!
And time's up.
We'll now decide which eleven of you will move on to the next round.
I've never seen anyone eat as much as you do.
Hm.
I don't understand why you're not eating anything.
The food won't stay down, because I'm too nervous about whether or not I made it.
I didn't get any time on the ball to show him what I can do.
Like at all.
So Ichiro Tachibana,
Akinori Kanida,
Yudai Hasegawa,
and Lee Yong-suk.
I think all of these guys are strong choices.
Tsukishima, what are your thoughts so far?
Aisaku Otomo!
I thought he was very unique.
I remember that guy,
but I don't remember him making any moves that stood out to me.
Yeah, but I was thinking of his behavior both on and off the field.
Do you guys know what I mean?
I suppose.
Me too.
Even before the tryouts got underway,
he was going around chatting up his competitors.
He seemed rather focused on the white jerseys,
especially the ones with numbers closest to his.
Do you get it?
He picked out guys who were most likely to be teammates for the minigame.
Focused his attention on them
so he could gauge personalities and playing styles in advance.
I don't know about that.
I do.
I'm telling you, he'll be worth it.
Trust me, he's a shrewd one.
Also, he's the only one I saw trying to motivate his team
when the chips were down and the stakes were high.
All I know is we're short on midfielders.
We'll keep him.
The biggest question mark is Ashito Aoi.
Hey, seems like collectively we're quite split on him.
Wait, it's you.
I'm sorry.
I didn't realize you were the lunch lady.
What?
I'm not.
You just saw me helping out at tryouts.
I'm volunteering here today.
We're probably the same age, too.
Stop distracting me.
No more seconds for you.
What?
Don't act so surprised.
If you make the cut, then you'll have to play another game right away.
And on top of that, you've had plenty of fried food already,
which is hard to digest and will only slow you down.
Hey, it doesn't make any sense for a reckless guy like you to think that far ahead.
I doubt you could pull off a pass like that.
Tell the truth.
Was it just a dumb accident?
To be honest with you, I'm not exactly sure myself.
They'd completely owned us up until that point.
So I stopped and looked around the field, trying to come up with something to do.
It's a weird habit of mine, but looking around the field calms me down.
I don't really remember much after that.
My body just sort of reacted to it.
That's awesome!
So it was intuition!
Hmm?
I'm so relieved.
I knew it wasn't something a normal teenager could copy.
What?
My all-time favorite player said the game was always right there.
Whatever he was doing, soccer was on his mind.
During training, during a match, even when he wasn't playing.
Like it was baked into his soul.
He never stopped thinking about it.
Nothing was more important.
When something's completely part of you like that, it comes naturally, without having to think.
He believed that feeling was the indication that you've truly mastered your craft.
He'd say it's similar to intuition, but not quite the same thing.
Best of luck.
And remember, a man is but a thinking reed.
Hi, I'm Hana Ichijo.
Nice to meet you.
I'm manager Fukuda's sister.
Step-sister.
Hmm.
Goal!
23-year-old Tatsuya Fukuda is unstoppable!
He just sent a laser beam of a long pass upfield from inside his team's end!
Good afternoon, candidates.
May I have your attention, please?
We have made our decision on who will move on to the next stage.
If your name is called, please make your way to the field.
Thank you.
Next time on Awashi, the final test begins.